寂静岭PT是一款谜一般的现象级游戏
PT is the definition of an enigmatic phenomenon.
当这款试玩版游戏在PS4平台发布时
When the small game or teaser demo launched on the Playstation 4,
完全没有任何提示 任何宣发 任何发布会
there was no warning, no forward, no press release, hell,
甚至据所有人所知 游戏里所谓的制作组也根本不存在
even the studio listed as having developed it didn't exist, as far as anybody could tell.
简单来说 这游戏就像凭空冒出来一样
Simply, the game was a complete unknown coming out of nowhere, from seemingly no one.
这样的一个开始就已经够奇葩的了
Now, that by itself is very suspicious and strange to begin with.
你或许可能会以为这游戏是某个steam上青睐之光的作品
Maybe you could explain it away, if it were some sort of steam green light title that ...
由西伯利亚哪个工棚里做出来的
was from some unknown developer in the middle of nowhere in Siberia.
但这款游戏的质量却相当好
But in this case, the game was actually pretty good.
虽然流程很短 但游戏画面 从一开始就让人感觉牛逼
Granted it was short, but graphically, the second it was booted up, it was outstanding.
当时还是2014年的8月 这种画面简直是现象级的
especially at the time back in August of 2014, this was graphically phenomenal.
作为对比 那年还出了《刺客信条：大革命》
To put it in perspective, that was the same year that Assassin's Creed Unity launched,
该游戏在当时已经是令玩家激动到窒息的游戏了
and that was considered to be one of the most ... breathtaking games ever.
当然游戏发售后才发现 确实挺窒息的
I mean and then the game launched, and people changed their mind on that.
而PT这款凭空出现的游戏 画面精美 品质上乘 甚至在整个行业都是领先的
But the point is that PT came out of nowhere and looked fantastic, cutting edge, even industry leading.
同时 它又非常有创造力 非常独特
In addition, it was creative and very, very unique.
为避免大家不了解 或者有点忘了 提醒一下 PT的场景是一条无限循环的走廊
In case you're not aware, or if you just need a jog to your memory, PT is set in a never ending hallway.
玩家多次经过这条走廊 基于每次的行动 会有些许的变化
The player goes through a ton of different cycles of this hallway with its slowly changing and updating,
based on the things that you do.
这样平凡的场景却时时刻刻让人感觉到不安与恐惧
The setting is equally unsettling and terrifying, all at the same time of being remarkably mundane.
真的 你找一个碳基生物做一个恐怖游戏的场景
I mean, seriously, if you were going to design a horror game,
肯定不会想到把你家房子前厅和走廊设计成直接相连的样式
chances are one of the last places you would think to place it
would be in the front foyer of your house with the hallway directly adjacent.
这太怪了 但实际效果却好得不行
It's very bizarre, and yet it works so well.
这款游戏真的够罕见的
Really, it's one of those rare forms of horror games
乍一看完全不像是想吓唬人
that doesn't really seem as though it's trying to scare you.
而事实上 即使放到现在也很罕见
In fact, it's really rare nowadays.
我写这视频的台本时 要发售的一款恐怖题材的恐怖游戏
As of the time of writing this script,
the most recent horror game that was to come out, dedicated to the horror genre
是《黑相集》系列的《黑相集：稀望镇》
was within The Dark Pictures Anthology, specifically the game Little Hope,
如果你让我做那款游戏的评测
which ... if you want me to do a critique,
那我可不困了 我可要好好告诉你《黑相集》系列有多垃圾
breaking down why I hate these Dark Pictures games, I would be happy to do it.
那阵还干过不少烂事 因为我真气坏了
There are some of the worst things I've ever done, I was legitimately upset.
我去年还花钱买了《黑相集：棉兰号》 当然那是题外话
I spent money on Man of Medan back last year, but that's beside the point.
重点是 这系列游戏真的很烂 他们绞尽脑汁来吓唬你
Point is, those games are terrible, and they try so hard to scare you
结果却一丁点都不吓人
that it ends up being totally unterrifying.
反观PT 游戏并没有什么刻意吓唬人的元素
On the other side of the corn is PT, a game that doesn't do almost anything to scare you.
完全没有束手束脚的操作
It also doesn't do anything to hold your hand.
这点我们马上会提
Something that we're going to talk a little bit more about in a second.
一个游戏的核心应当是有某种机制在里面的
You see a game at its core has to have some sort of mechanic,
应当有某种需要玩家去解决的难题
some sort of struggle that the player is trying to resolve.
如果没有要解决的目标 或是没有任何难度 那这款游戏就会变成步行模拟器
A game that doesn't have any sort of struggle or difficulty, is ... just a walking simulator.
很多玩家也因此对某些游戏表达了失望与批评
And many people have expressed frustration and levied this very criticism against certain games
诸如顽皮狗的系列游戏 或者《死亡搁浅》这样的游戏
such as Naughty Dog titles, or even something like Death stranding
因为他们评价游戏是“步行模拟器 没有足够要解决的难题”
for being a quote, unquote, "walking simulator: a game that doesn't have enough struggle".
另一种说法是如果游戏没有足够的难度
Another way of putting this is when a game doesn't have enough difficulty,
就会让玩家无法足够参与进游戏中来
it ... leads the player into a situation where they don't have to engage,
无法与游戏共进退
hardly at all with the game itself to progress.
玩家应该和游戏在同一条船上 共同从A到B
Effectively, they're on train tracks, going from point A to point B.
这种情况下你能讲出一个有趣的故事 但很难能让玩家参与其中
And you can tell an interesting story that way, but it's not actually that engaging.
也因此 这样的游戏我通常称之为“视觉小说” 而不是一般的电子游戏
It's why, I would say games such as that are much closer to "visual novels" than they are - video games.
游戏对我来说需要某种程度的互动
Games to me require some level of interaction.
而现在 PT非常精巧地骑在了游戏与视觉小说的那条分界线上
Now PT straddles that line between game and visual storytelling very finely.
因为游戏中有你必须去互动才能解决的谜题
Specifically, because it has puzzles that you have to interact with to progress.
所以你不可能绕着相同的走廊走他50圈然后通关游戏
You can't just walk through the hallway fifty times and experience the game start to finish.
你必须切身参与进游戏的某种机制中去 才能推进游戏
You have to actively engage in certain mechanisms in order to progress,
而PT这款游戏背后的机制实在是非常非常让人捉摸不透
that being said, the mechanisms that you have to engage with are VERY VERY vague.
模糊到相当多的玩家不去查攻略 查外部资料的情况下根本没法通关
In fact, it's so vague that many people are unable to go through this game from start to finish
without looking up some sort of guide or receiving some level of assistance from an outside source.
最好的例子就是整个游戏里结尾的谜题
The most specific example of this would be the final puzzle of the teaser, that is PT.
小岛秀夫作为整个游戏体验的设计者与导演
You see Hideo Kojima, the lead designer and director of this whole experience
他认为游戏的关键是不断的试错
expected that trial and error was going to be key.
他在涉及所有谜题与游戏体验时
And he designed all of these puzzles, and this experience in general,
首先想到的就是这点
with that first and foremost in his mind.
另外 小岛秀夫当时估计游戏界要花大概一周才能破解游戏里的谜题
Furthermore, Kojima also expected it to take roughly a week
for the gaming community to finish the taser trailer.
但根据2014年的一些统计来看
Though, by some accounts, from back in 2014,
显然一些玩家只花了几小时就通关了
apparently, some people only required a few hours to get through all of these puzzles,
无论当时是巧合还是几个主播一起合作完成还是其他方法
whether it was coincidence or working together with other streamers,
or whatever it may have been at the time.
反正留下来的记录太少了
It's pretty much been lost to history at this point.
但有报告说有玩家只花五小时就通关了
But there were reports some people were able to get through in as few as four to five hours.
我对游戏本身的谜题看法很矛盾
Now I'm really conflicted on these puzzles.
它们太模糊了 玩家只能靠瞎蒙才能找到某些解决办法
They are SO vague that it requires the player to effectively guess
in order to come up with some sort of solution
要么就是问问通关的人他们怎么过的
or to seek out advice from others who have already solved it.
这些对我来讲都没什么意思
Neither of those are particularly exciting to me.
我玩游戏还是更愿意靠自己解决这些谜题
If I'm playing a video game, I would like the ability to solve it myself
不搞那些来回试错后瞎猫碰死耗子的狗屎运
without blind luck in the form of trial and error, hoping I stumble into the solution,
我也不想切出游戏上谷歌搜索 看看别人怎么通关的
or requiring the advice of somebody else
that takes me out of the game and on to Google to try and find solutions to a game.
我觉得这样就没意思了
That ... that's ... not fun to me.
但或许有些玩家认为这样是也是合理有效的游戏机制
But perhaps you find that perfectly legitimate and the valid gameplay mechanic.
我说不好 欢迎在评论区讨论
I don't know, let me know in the comments.
不过我们还是先来看看游戏中具体的谜题
But let's look at these puzzles specifically.
游戏结尾的谜题异常的复杂 需要各种瞎蒙各种试错才能解决
This particular puzzle is incredibly convoluted and requires, by all states measures,
trial and error to solve just blindly.
玩家们已经测试过 这个谜题有多种解决办法
Now there are actually multiple solutions to the final puzzle that people have tested,
能够引导角色到最终安全的地点 并结束PT的游玩过程
and found moves the game into the final safe state, leading into the end of the Playable Teaser.
简单来讲 玩家需要等到走廊里午夜的钟声响起
You see, basically, what happens is the player has to wait
until the clock strikes midnight in the hallway.
听到钟声后 玩家还要有麦克风或者头戴耳机插进PS4手柄上
Once this has happened, the player also needs to make sure that they have a microphone or a headset
plugged into the Dualshock 4 controller.
最后 我们要想办法让一个不知道在哪的小宝宝笑三声
And ultimately, what we're trying to do is to get a baby somewhere to laugh, 3 times.
之后 电话会响起
Once this happens, a phone will ring,
引导我们到游戏的结尾部分
which will lead us into the final portion of the teaser.
第一次笑声触发方法是向任意方向走十步
The way you trigger the first laugh is by walking exactly ten paces in any direction,
然后停下
and stopping at that point.
之后你会在一秒后听到一声宝宝的笑声
Once that happens, you wait a second, and you'll hear the baby laugh.
别忘了 要在午夜钟声响起后再做
Again, this has to be specifically after the clock strikes midnight.
之后要触发第二次笑声 这里就开始有很多种方法了
The next step is to trigger the second laugh, which is where these multiple methods come in.
目前来看有几种达成的办法
There's multiple ways that this seems to be able to be done.
第一种是将麦克风插进手柄
The first method is to have the microphone plugged into the controller.
插好后 玩家要自己主动寻找Lisa 就是游戏里那个特别吓人的鬼混角色
With that plugged in, the player will seek out Lisa, the spooky gully, ghosty character in the game,
玩家要试图找到她的声音是从哪里发出的
trying to find where her sounds are emanating from.
在恐怖游戏里让玩家主动去找一个特别吓人的东西 简直了都
I know it's crazy in a horror game to actively, like
seek out the scary thing that's making creepy sounds,
但在这个方法里 你只能这样做
but in this method, that's what you have to do.
游戏中玩到这里的时候 她可能出现在走廊中三个地方之一
Now there are three main areas that she can appear at
within the hallway at this particular stage of this puzzle.
其一 她可能出现在收音机中 听起来像是电流声
For one, she can appear in the radio, and this is going to sound like sort of an electronic static,
听着像是里面有个女的在笑
and it'll sound as though there's a woman laughing.
其二 她可能出现在电话中 和收音机一样 听起来有电流声
The second place would be in the phone, and just like the radio, it's filled with static,
但电话里听到的是很粗的呼吸声
but you hear a heavy breathing.
最后 她还可能出现在镜子中
And lastly she might appear within the mirror.
这时我们听不见电流声 但却能听到一个女的哭得梨花带雨
In this case, we don't hear static but just distorted sounds of a woman crying.
真的 我这一边念台本 脑中想着自己在PT里的画面
Dude, I'm not ... I'm not even joking like ...
I'm reading through these things that I found within the teaser,
就已经浑身不寒而栗了 简直……
and I'm like getting goose bumps and freaked out, just ...
光是读这些内容就已经能感觉到游戏有多吓人了
Like, I have the pictures in my head of what these things are and is freaking me out, just reading it.
太离谱了
This is ... ridiculous.
译注：凌晨四点做这这个字幕也吓得不行了
这也是PT的可怕之处 光是读这视频的台本我就吓得不行了
This is how impactful the teaser was that just reading a script about it, I'm getting goose bumps.
不知道大家看到视频中的画面 听到我说的这些有没有被吓到
I don't know if you're getting goose bumps
like watching this footage and hearing about all these things,
但游戏能做到这些真的很牛逼
but it's amazing what this game is able to do.
！！！前方视频画面Lisa高能！！！
同时大家还要知道 在刚刚所说的这些进行中时
Now also, bear in mind with all of these things,
Lisa随时可以突然出现在你面前攻击玩家 玩家只能回到安全屋重新开始
Lisa can jump out and attack the player, which will cause you to restart that safe state.
所以你不但要在游戏中有所行动 还要小心突然闹鬼
So you have to do this balancing act of slowly moving towards the haunted item.
为了那第二声宝宝笑 玩家需要眼观六路耳听八方
Listening to it, interacting with it in order for the second baby laugh to trigger.
同时还要避开真正的Lisa
All while trying to avoid the actual Lisa,
因为她说不定就在走廊什么地方或者楼上哪里正盯着你呢
who is going to be in the hallway somewhere or in the upper landing, watching you.
当你找到声音来源 来到它旁边 检查它
But when you figure out where this sound is coming to, you head to the item, examine it,
“闹鬼”才算结束
and eventually the quote, unquote, "haunting" will end.
这时就会触发第二声宝宝笑
This is when the second baby laugh will trigger.
不过玩家还发现有另外两种方法可以触发第二声宝宝笑
However, there are two other methods
that people have found can also lead to the second baby laugh triggering.
方法2 当你进入最终这条走廊后
Method number two is that once you enter the final loop,
立即前往数字钟 等它时间过午夜
you immediately go to the digital clock and wait for it to change to midnight.
午夜钟响后
Now once the bell hits midnight,
你会听到刚刚说的要么哭要么喘粗气的声音
you'll hear the ghostly wailing and the heavy breathing and everything that we just discussed.
然后你走向出口旁的老收音机 检查它
You go over to the old radio near the exit and inspect it,
然后马上去窗户旁边的电话 也检查一下
you then immediately jump over to the telephone near the window and inspect that too.
如果一切正确 就会触发第一声宝宝笑 因为中间刚好是十步
This, if done right, will trigger the first laugh from the baby, because it should equal 10 paces.
之后 你要向连接PS4手柄的麦克风制造一些噪音
At that point, you begin making noise into the microphone that's plugged into the PS4.
你可以对着麦克风尖叫 哭两嗓子 随便弄点声音……
You can scream, you can cry, you can just make up randomly, crap, single wraps on ...
whatever you want to do.
最后 就会听到额外两声宝宝笑
Until eventually, two more baby laughs are triggered.
但根据一些玩家反馈 这个操作可能要花很久 可能要对着麦克风说上一分多钟
But it, according to some people, this can take a while, like ... 90 seconds of non stop talking.
两声笑声触发后
Once the second laugh triggers,
电话会响起 手柄也会开始震动
the phone will start ringing, and the controller will start vibrating.
你走到电话旁 检查它 你会听到电话那头说
You then go over to the phone, inspect it, at which point you will hear a voice simply say
“你被选中了”
"You have been chosen".
之后最后一道门打开 你就可以离开了
Then the final door opens and you can exit,
观看到最后的寂静岭的预告片
viewing the final trailer for what was going to be Silent Hills.
第三种 也就是最后一种触发第二声宝宝笑的方法
And the third and final method for getting the second baby laughter trigger,
是在玩家听到午夜钟声 并完成走十步的步骤后
is that after the chimes strike midnight and you've completed the ten step laughter sequence,
主动去寻找 尝试通过麦克风和她交流
Lisa you seek out Lisa, and attempt to communicate with her through your microphone.
换句话说 你要尝试离她尽可能地近 同时还要跟她说些诸如
In other words, you try to get as close to her as possible, while also saying things such as,
“氦 李姐 最近咋样 哭啥呀 要帮忙不”
"Hello? Lisa, hello, help me, help me, Lisa, let me help you, Lisa."
这样也能触发第二声宝宝笑 继续推进游戏
Things like that trigger the second laugh, allowing you to move on.
上述除了第二种方法外 玩家听到第二声宝宝笑后
Now in all but method two, once the second laugh is triggered,
必须保持原地不动
the player must freeze.
不能移动 不能调整视角
You do not move. Don't adjust the camera.
也不能动手柄
Don't even move the controller,
因为手柄里的陀螺仪也能检测到移动 从而触发Lisa朝你扑面而来
because the gyroscope can be registered as movement for Lisa and the haunting.
几秒后 手柄会开始震动
After a few seconds, the controller will start to vibrate.
你还要继续保持不动
Again, you need to remain completely motionless.
最终 手柄震动停止 触发了第三声宝宝笑
Eventually, the vibration stops and the third laugh triggers.
笑声触发后 电话响起
Once the third laugh triggers, the phone rings,
你过去接电话 听到你被选中了
you pick it up, hear that you're chosen
然后走到最后一个门 看最后一段预告片 结束这个demo
and move on out to the final teaser trailer, finishing the demo.
如果你听完这些感觉这也太离谱太复杂了 那你说对了
Now, if that all sounds remarkably convoluted and complicated, you're right, it is.
实际上 PT的最终“解决方案”
In fact, the final quote, unquote "solution" to PT
从游戏demo公布以后就一直争论不断
has actually been the subject of a lot of debate since the Demo's initial release.
尤其是游戏里第二声哭声的触发方法简直千奇百怪
Specifically, because the second laugh seems to be triggered by a ton of different things.
甚至有玩家反馈说在游戏暂停菜单里也触发出来了
Some players have apparently even reported it occurring in a pause screen,
同时又有玩家坚持说跟鬼魂隔空喊话是必要环节
while others say that talking to the ghost is a necessary component,
其他玩家则说这些都是完全随机的
and others also claim that it's actually entirely random.
我的意思是 大家必须承认
Which, I mean, you gotta admit it would be really funny
如果这一切是只是完全随机的
if all of this was just completely random,
而我们所有人都只是在做阅读理解的话会多么有趣
and we are just reading into all of these different things.
就像你完成最后这个谜题时候的某些步骤某些动作
Like steps and actions, you need to complete this final puzzle
实际上可能只是随机触发的 比如……
when in reality it just triggers some point randomly between, like ...
从第一分钟到第三分钟的动作才算 而且你做什么都无所谓
a minute and 3 minutes, and it doesn't matter what you do.
我个人其实不太相信这样的说法 我更愿意相信游戏不是随机的
I ... I don't think that's the case, I think more likely than not,
应该还是有特定的方法来触发这些东西的
there are specific methods that you need to pursue in order for this to trigger.
以我游玩PT的游戏体验来讲
In my experience, testing, the Playable Teaser,
游戏的确依赖于某些特定的操作 但……
it does actually require specific inputs, but ...
我又知道些什么呢
what do I know.
现在的问题是
Now the question is,
在游戏中设置如此晦涩的谜题是否合理
whether or not it's justifiable to have puzzles that are this obscure in a video game.
我的意思是 玩家解决这些谜题的唯一办法真的只有盲目地尝试
I mean, really, the only way you could realistically solve these puzzles
would be by way of blind look.
在没有任何攻略信息给你的情况下
How would you figure out with no knowledge or information given to you,
谁能想出玩家需要在任何方向准确地走十步这种事？
that you need to walk exactly ten paces in any direction?
更何况 走完十步你还要完全静止不动 等到第二声宝宝笑
Furthermore, once that happens, you need to freeze until a second baby laughs.
你要执行上述三种方法之一才能触发最后的步骤
And then you need to engage in one of those three methods that we just described
in order to trigger the final steps.
我不知道你怎么想的 但对我来说 我不得不问这样一个问题
I don't know about you, but for me, I have to ask the question is
盲目疯狂试图解决一个没有线索指示的谜题
frustratedly and frantically trying to get past a puzzle that is no clues, instruction or or guide
究竟是好的游戏设计 还是纯粹在折腾玩家？
actually good game design? or is it just needlessly convoluted?
我想说这样的游戏设计其实很糟糕
I'd say it's really bad game design.
但这样的设计用来营造恐怖氛围却惊人的合适
But amazingly enough, it's actually really good horror design.
当我们谈论小岛秀夫的游戏时 必须要了解到他的游戏的大主题
You see, when we talk about any Hideo Kojima game, we have to mention meta theming within the title.
小岛秀夫想要消除给玩家带来的一切舒适感
Kojima wanted to remove any and all comfort,
包括游戏设计的一些主干内容
and this included some of the staples of video game design.
他想让大家忘记是谁做的这款游戏
He wanted to remove the knowledge of who developed the game.
他想让大家忘记一切玩家在发布之前的预告片中对游戏的了解
He wanted to remove any sort of prior knowledge
that comes up with hype or trailers or knowledge of the game prior to release.
你想去掉抬头显示元素 因为如果你知道你的健康值 知道自己制造了多少噪音
You wanted to get rid of heads up display elements, because those can be comforting
if you know what your health is, if you know how much noise you're making,
甚至哪怕是一个小地图 也是玩家可以依靠的元素 也会提升游戏的舒适感
if you even have just a small mini map that can be a crutch that the player can lean on.
而当然 在推进PT中故事的推进时 小岛也想消除任何游戏的指示
And of course he wanted to remove any semblance of instruction
when it comes to the progression within the Playable Teaser's story.
起初看起来很简单 只要沿着无限循环的走廊走下去就好
It seems simple, at first, just keep walking through an infinite hallway,
但之后你不得不开始猜测 开始解谜才能通过
but you'll eventually run into circumstances
when you have to start guessing in order to get through.
不让玩家看到清晰的游戏指引
Now removing a clear and guided experience from the player,
让玩家对推进游戏进程感觉困难无比 毫无头绪
making it very convoluted and difficult and even mysterious as to how to progress
至少在我看来是非常好的游戏核心设计
is very good core design, at least in my opinion.
这使得在玩家的脑海中一直存在着不确定性
That makes it, so there's constant uncertainty within the player's mind
即玩家在想取得进展时并不清楚他们目前在游戏的整体结构中的位置
as to how they're going to progress if they are going to progress
and where they are currently within the game's overall structure.
也因此 我之前也提到过 小岛秀夫的游戏和一般的电子游戏有一些不同
It's one of the reasons I've said before
that Hideo Kojima games are kind of different from ... video games.
他们几乎跳出了我们在游戏中期望看到的常规界限
They step almost outside of the regular bounds of what we would expect to see within a game,
因为他的设计思路早已跳出了人们的常规思维
because he thinks very much outside the box.
这会导致游戏本身可能质量不高但体验非常有趣
This leads to games that can be bad games but very interesting experiences.
同样 粉丝们也总是可以为他的任何游戏做辩护
Now in the same vein, fans can always defend any of his games or any title for that matter,
只需说“这只是游戏主题的一部分”
simply by saying it's just part of the theme of the game,
“你要是不喜欢说明你没玩懂”
and if you don't like it, you just don't get it.
这句话放到PT上说得通
This can be used for PT,
放到《死亡搁浅》上也说得通
it can be used for Death Stranding
甚至放到像《最后生还者 第II章》这样的游戏中也说得通
or even a game such as The Last of Us Part II.
如果你不喜欢他们在作品中为颠覆玩家期望而做的所有黑暗而真实的叙事
If you don't like all of the dark, gritty narrative things
that they did within that title to mess with the player or to subvert expectations,
那粉丝总会出来说
fans can always just say,
“如果你不喜欢某某角色死了 那你只是没看懂而已”
"well, if you didn't like that that character died, you just don't get it."
而其他人可能会说
While other people might say,
“可我说的不是这个问题
"well, it's not a matter of that,
我想说的是这是不是编剧为了讲好故事而做出的正确选择”
it's just a matter of whether or not that was the right choice for communicating the story
that the writers were trying to communicate."
这确实是避免批评或积极讨论一个故事的免死金牌
It really is the ultimate get out of jail, free card
for avoiding criticism or active discussion on a story.
也因此我经常尽量避免在游戏核心主题设计决策上作出评判
And it's for this reason that I tried to avoid
justifying design decisions based on these meta themes.
就像我说的 我认为PT的恐怖体验非常棒
Like I said, I think PT is an incredible horror experience,
但作为一个游戏 我觉得它还缺很多东西
while as a game, it leaves a lot to be lacking.
但这并不是说这游戏有什么毛病
But that's not necessarily to say that there's anything wrong with it.
我一直坚信电子游戏是人类讲故事的一种自然而然延伸出的媒介
I am a fervent believer that video games are the natural progression of narrative storytelling.
盘古开天之时 我们围坐在篝火边
First, we all sat around campfires
讲述着猎杀猛犸象剑齿虎的故事
and told stories of hunting down mammoths and Saber-tooth tigers,
之后我们有了文字 开始将这些故事记录下来
then we moved on, and we started writing those stories down.
后来 我们将这些记录下来的故事在其他人面前演绎出来
Eventually, we took those stories that were written down
and started performing them in front of each other
以话剧的形式展现在一大群人面前
in plays and big presentations in front of large groups of people.
后来越来越多的人学会了读书 学会了写字
Then, once people were able to read and write much more ubiquitously,
我们将这些故事写成小说 编撰成册
we took those stories, put them into books and novels,
其中一些故事家喻户晓到无数人未曾设想的程度
and distributed them to the masses beyond anything that anybody could have possibly ever imagined.
之后到了19世纪末20世纪初
Then in the late 19th and early 20th centuries,
我们将这些故事搬到了银幕上
we took those stories and converted them into film.
我们以一种超越所有人想象的 更具吸引力的方式讲述这些故事
We told those stories in a way that was much more engaging,
beyond which anybody had ever seen before.
同时我们还将这些电影向全世界各地发行
Furthermore, we could also distribute those films all throughout the world.
电影流行开后 我们又开始看电视直播
And as film became more and more common, we started broadcasting things live
抱着电视 我们度过了无数夜晚
and actively every single night in the form of television.
随后来到了90年代末 21世纪初
And then in the late 90s and early 2000s,
我们真的开始将讲故事这件事搬到了电子游戏上
we really started to push narrative storytelling within video games.
因为有几个非常聪明的人意识到我们可以用互动的方式讲故事
Because a few very smart people realized that we could tell stories in an interactive way,
这将为人们带来前所未有的沉浸体验
which would take the immersion level beyond that which anybody had ever seen before.
而且说实话 直到最近我们才慢慢意识到这件事带来的好处
And to be honest, just now we're starting to see the benefits of that work
比如《最后生还者 第II章》《死亡搁浅》这些游戏
in the form of games such as The Last of Us Part II, Death Stranding,
还有《赛博朋克2077》 当然得等它修到能愉快游玩的时候
Cyberpunk 2077, to a certain extent, when it's playable that is.
还有很多很多其他游戏 它们讲故事的方式放在以前只会存在于想象中
And many MANY other games that tell stories in a way that was only imaginable before.
我想说的是 电子游戏不仅仅是
What I'm trying to say is that I think video games are bigger
无脑向玩家灌输某种成就感满足感的工具
than just gameplay loops that are meant to instill some sense of accomplishment within the player.
有些现象级游戏是这样的 做得也很棒
Some games do that, and it's fantastic and phenomenal.
我自己也超级喜欢《使命召唤：战区》
I'm as big a fan of War Zone as the next guy.
但另一方面来讲 电子游戏可以用来讲故事
But in other cases, video games are able to tell stories,
而且它为我们带来的体验绝非其他媒介可以媲美
and make us feel things in a way that no other media could possibly do.
也因此 我认为PT并不仅仅是一款游戏
And it's for that reason that I think PT isn't just a game,
它是一种别样的体验
it's an experience.
我们能够拥有这样的作品 何其有幸
And it's one that we were very lucky to have, way back in the day.
我想说的就是这些 感谢大家的观看
But that's it for me. Thank you for watching.
我爱你们 欢迎关注我的频道 我们下期视频见
I love you all, follow me on all my social media, and I'll see you in the next video.